<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Damien DataSci Blog on Damien DataSci Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Damien DataSci Blog on Damien DataSci Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of personality and social context on willingness to share emotion information on social media</title>
      <link>/publication/2018-socialmedia-psyarxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018-socialmedia-psyarxiv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of emotions in product acceptance: Evaluation of the cognitive, motivational and subjective component</title>
      <link>/publication/2017-acceptance-pto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2017-acceptance-pto/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison of Three Commercial Systems for Automatic Recognition of Spontaneous Facial Expressions</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-cere/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-cere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SYMPOSIUM 2: Affect Recognition in Humans versus Machines: Current Issues and Future Challenges
&lt;em&gt;Convener: Eva Krumhuber, University College London, UK&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT: Automatic facial expression recognition systems can provide important information about our emotions and how they change over time. While the use of automatic systems has seen a steady increase over the last years, their classification results have not yet been systematically compared. The aim of this research was to test commercial software packages from Affectiva, Kairos and Microsoft companies in terms of their recognition accuracy. For this, we focused on spontaneous and dynamic facial expressions as provided by the DynEmo database –Disgust, Fear, Joy, and Surprise. In order to compare the classification results, we calculated the systems’ ratio of True positives (only the target label is recognised), False positives (the target label as well as a non-target label is recognised), True negatives (no label is recognised) and False negatives (target label is not recognised whereas a non-target label is).
The results of the comparison between the systems showed comparable detection rates in term of True positives and False positives. However, their detection rates of False negatives and True negatives significantly differed between the different recognition systems. Specifically, systems were not equal in their tendency to detect non-target labels erroneously as well as in their tendency to not detect any emotion label. When examining emotion recognition accuracy for each video/emotion, videos with higher recognition accuracy were those that depicted as joyful facial expression. Other facial expressions resulted in a proportion of target emotion detection statistically equal or lower than the detection of non-target emotion.
These results suggest that systems are not equivalent in their ability to detect specific spontaneous emotions. Therefore, users of such systems have to be aware of the strengths as well as of the potential limits of the data provided by automatic emotion recognition systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Analysis of Automatic Facial Expressions Recognition ‘in the Wild’ Using Generalized Additive Mixed Models and Significant Zero Crossing of the Derivatives</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-bhci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-bhci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT: The analysis of facial expressions is currently a favoured method of inferring experienced emotion, and consequently significant efforts are currently being made to develop improved facial expression recognition techniques. Among these new techniques, those which allow the automatic recognition of facial expression appear to be most promising. This paper presents a new method of facial expression analysis with a focus on the continuous evolution of emotions using Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMM) and Significant Zero Crossing of the Derivatives (SiZer). The time-series analysis of the emotions experienced by participants watching a series of three different online videos suggests that analysis of facial expressions at the overall level may lead to misinterpretation of the emotional experience whereas non-linear analysis allows the significant expressive sequences to be identified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Body Area Network of Physiological Measures “In the Wild”: A case study with zipline activity</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-mb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-mb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ABSTRACT: With the development of wearable sensors, it is now possible to assess the dynamic progression of physiological rhythms such as heart rate, breathing rate or galvanic skin response in ways and places and during certain activities that were previously not possible due to cost and reliability. This paper investigates the physiological changes when participating in a zipline activity. Despite the advances in sensor technology, the statistical analysis of such physiological signals remains a challenge for data analysts. This paper presents a workflow encompassing the whole process with the goal of obtaining a range of best fitting models to analyse the patterns given by these measurements “in the wild”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DynEmo</title>
      <link>/project/dynemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dynemo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DynEmo is a database available to the scientific community (&lt;a href=&#34;https://dynemo.univ-grenoble-alpes.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://dynemo.univ-grenoble-alpes.fr/&lt;/a&gt;). It contains dynamic and natural emotional facial expressions (EFEs) displaying subjective affective states rated by both the expresser and observers. Methodological and contextual information is provided for each expression. This multimodal corpus meets psychological, ethical, and technical criteria. It is quite large, containing two sets of 233 and 125 recordings of EFE of ordinary Caucasian people (ages 25 to 65, 182 females and 176 males) filmed in natural but standardized conditions. In the Set 1, EFE recordings are associated with the affective state of the expresser (self-reported after the emotion inducing task, using dimensional, action readiness, and emotional labels items). In the Set 2, EFE recordings are both associated with the affective state of the expresser and with the time line (continuous annotations) of observers’ ratings of the emotions displayed throughout the recording. The time line allows any researcher interested in analysing non-verbal human behavior to segment the expressions into small emotion excerpts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oudjat, a configurable and usable annotation tool for the study of emotional stimuli</title>
      <link>/publication/2015-oudjat-ijhcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2015-oudjat-ijhcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cadres et méthodes d’analyse des émotions suscitées par des produits innovants : Une revue bibliographique</title>
      <link>/publication/2015-acceptabilite-innovatio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2015-acceptabilite-innovatio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DynEmo: A video database of natural facial expressions of emotions</title>
      <link>/publication/2013-dynemo-ijma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2013-dynemo-ijma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of facial designs interfaces on dynamic emotional recognition</title>
      <link>/publication/2013-interface-jmui/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2013-interface-jmui/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quelques critères d’utilisation d’un outil d’évaluation automatique de synthèses de cours à distance</title>
      <link>/publication/2012-critere-re/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2012-critere-re/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Un environnement personnel d&#39;apprentissage évaluant des distances épistémiques et dialogiques</title>
      <link>/publication/2011-environement-ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2011-environement-ds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
