<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Damien DataSci Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Damien DataSci Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>`dplyrshortcut` package: How to create keyboard shortcuts for dplyr functions on RStudio IDE </title>
      <link>/post/dplyrshortcut-package-how-to-create-keyboard-shortcuts-for-dplyr-functions-on-rstudio-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dplyrshortcut-package-how-to-create-keyboard-shortcuts-for-dplyr-functions-on-rstudio-ide/</guid>
      <description>People are saying that if you are repeating a code more than twice, then make a function for it. The idea of dplyrshortcut is that if you are using a function more than twice, then use a keyboard shortcut.
InstallationYou can install the development version of dplyrshortcut with the devtools package.
# install.packages(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;)devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;damien-dupre/dplyrshortcut&amp;quot;)Usedplyrshortcut add functions in RStudio IDE’s Addins section.
Then, in order to add the shortcut to your keyboard, use the Rstudio IDE: Tools&amp;gt;Modify Keyboard Shortcuts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to organize a wedding with R: google place API, google drive, web scraping and automatic emails</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-organise-a-wedding-with-r-google-search-api-google-drive-web-scraping-and-automatic-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-organise-a-wedding-with-r-google-search-api-google-drive-web-scraping-and-automatic-emails/</guid>
      <description>Organizing a wedding is … challenging but as Rusers we do have a major asset! One of the most challenging part is to find a venue. Indeed there are a lot of them but some are already booked for your date. So, in order to check if a venue is already booked I’ll show you how I made a list of possible venues with google search API, stored the list on google drive, web scrap for their emails and send them with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series clustering with Dynamic Time Warping (Part 2)</title>
      <link>/post/time-series-clustering-with-dynamic-time-warping-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-series-clustering-with-dynamic-time-warping-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Like every good movies, my previous blog post “Time series clustering with Dynamic Time Warping” deserves a sequel. In this Part 2, I will have a look at the athletes’ training plan for a marathon. Because marathons are such a demanding performance, most of athletes have a specific training plan to follow in order to be prepared. Many different training plan can be found on the web such as this one from the website www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A simple introduction to statistical test and statistical significance</title>
      <link>/post/a-simple-introduction-to-statistical-test-and-statistical-significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-simple-introduction-to-statistical-test-and-statistical-significance/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was asked to make a short presentation about how to introduce the idea of statistical test and statistical significance to students in marketing. The timing was very good because I just had red a blog post written by Stephen B. Heard called Why do we make statistics so hard for our students? which is exactly the way to follow. So I taken the main idea of this post and made a short presentation with R that you can find here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series clustering with Dynamic Time Warping</title>
      <link>/post/time-series-clustering-with-dynamic-time-warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time-series-clustering-with-dynamic-time-warp/</guid>
      <description>Many solutions for clustering time series are available with R and as usual the web is full of nice tutorials like Thomas Girke’s blog post, Rafael Irizarry and Michael Love’s book, Andrew B. Collier’s blog post, Peter Laurinec’s blog post, Dylan Glotzer’s lecture or Ana Rita Marques’s module.
Dynamic Time Warping (DTW) is one of these solutions. The main advantage of DTW is the possibility to group time series according their patterns or shapes even if these patterns are not synchronized (lag).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing blogdown, some insights from my own experience</title>
      <link>/post/publishing-blogdown-some-insights-from-my-own-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/publishing-blogdown-some-insights-from-my-own-experience/</guid>
      <description>Finally! My first post to my website is about to be live on the web! I’m always amazed by the possibilities offered by R and Rstudio and my first lines will thank this huge community which make the awesomeness real. However it’s not always easy to use and to apply these magnificent tools. Publishing a blogdown is a good example of a process that looks easy on the first sight but which can be tricky.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>